So let's compare the Perceptron algorithm and the Gradient Descent algorithm.
では パーセプトロンアルゴリズムと 勾配降下法を 比較してみましょう
In the Gradient Descent algorithm,
勾配降下法では
we take the weights and change them from Wi to
重みを 変更します  Wi が
Wi_ plus_ alpha_ times_ Y hat_ minus_ Y_ times_ Xi.
Wi + α(y-ŷ) Xi に なります
In the Perceptron algorithm,
パーセプトロンアルゴリズムでは
not every point changes weights,
各点で 重みが 変わるわけではなく
only the misclassified ones.
誤分類された点 だけです
Here, if X is misclassified,
ここで Xが 誤分類された場合
we'll change the weights by adding Xi to Wi if the point label is positive,
点のラベルが 正なら Wiに Xiを 加算し
and subtracting if negative.
負なら Wiから Xiを 引いて 重みを変更します
Now the question is, are these two things the same?
問題は この 2つが 同じかどうか です
Well, let's remember that in that Perceptron algorithm,
思い出してみると パーセプトロンアルゴリズムでは
the labels are one and zero.
ラベルは 0と 1です
And the predictions Y-hat are also one and zero.
予測値の ŷも 0と 1です
So, if the point is correct, classified,
そのため 点が 正しく分類された場合
then Y_ minus_ Y-hat is zero because Y is equal to Y-hat.
yと ŷは 等しいので y-ŷは ゼロとなります
Now, if the point is labeled blue,
次に 点のラベルが青の場合
then Y_ equals_ one.
y=1です
And if it's misclassified,
誤分類の場合
then the prediction must be Y-hat_ equals_ zero.
予測値 ŷはゼロで
So Y-hat_ minus_ Y is minus one.
ŷ-yは -1になります
Similarly, with the points labeled red,
同様に 点のラベルが赤の場合は
then Y_ equals_ zero and Y-hat_ equals_ one.
y=0 で ŷ=1 です
So, Y-hat_ minus_ Y_ equals_ one.
ということは ŷ-y=0 です
This may not be super clear right away.
これは すぐには わかりにくいかも 知れません
But if you stare at the screen for long enough,
でも 画面を ずっと 見つめていると
you'll realize that the right and the left are exactly the same thing.
右と左が 同じものであることに 気づくでしょう
The only difference is that in the left,
唯一 違う点は 左側では
Y-hat can take any number between zero and one,
ŷが 0と1の間の 任意の値で あり得る一方
whereas in the right,
右側では
Y-hat can take only the values zero or one.
ŷが 0か 1の いずれかであることです
It's pretty fascinating, isn't it?
面白いと 思いませんか
But let's study Gradient Descent even more carefully.
では 勾配降下法について よく調べてみましょう
Both in the Perceptron algorithm and the Gradient Descent algorithm,
パーセプトロンアルゴリズムと 勾配降下法では
a point that is misclassified tells a line to come closer because eventually,
誤分類された点が 線に 近づくよう 指示します
it wants the line to surpass it so it can be in the correct side.
線が その点を 追い越せば 点が正しい側に 移るからです
Now, what happens if the point is correctly classified?
点が 正しく分類された場合は どうでしょうか
Well, the Perceptron algorithm says do absolutely nothing.
その場合 パーセプトロンアルゴリズムは 何もしないよう 指示します
In the Gradient Descent algorithm,
勾配降下法では
you are changing the weights.
重みを 変更します
But what is it doing?
それには どんな意味があるのでしょうか
Well, if we look carefully,
よく 見てみると
what the point is telling the line,
点が 線に出している 指示は
is to go farther away.
「もっと 離れろ」です
And this makes sense, right?
納得ですよね?
Because if you're correctly classified,
正しく 分類されている点なら つまり
say, if you're a blue point in the blue region,
青い領域にある 青い点なら
you'd like to be even more into the blue region,
青い領域の もっと深いところへ 行けば
so your prediction is even closer to one,
推定値が 1に近づき
and your error is even smaller.
誤差は さらに小さくなります
Similarly, for a red point in the red region.
同じことが 赤い領域にある 赤い点についても 言えます
So it makes sense that the point tells the line to go farther away.
だから 点が 線に 離れるよう指示するのは 納得できることです
And that's precisely what the Gradient Descent algorithm does.
それこそが 勾配降下法のアルゴリズムです
The misclassified points asks the line to come closer and
誤分類された点は 線に 近づくよう 指示し
the correctly classified points asks the line to go farther away.
正しく分類された点は 線に 離れるよう 指示します
The line listens to all the points and takes steps in
線は すべての点の指示を 聞いて
such a way that it eventually arrives to a pretty good solution.
措置を講じ 最後には かなり良い解に 到達します